SADAF AMININIA FRONTEND DEVELOPER

09108730180

sadaf.amininiaa@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/sadafamininia | github.com/sadafamininia99

ABOUT ME

Highly motivated and ambitious front-end developer with 3 years of experience in developing such as JavaScript, React, Next.js, HTML, CSS, Sass, and Styled Components to build visually appealing and functional user interfaces. Familiar with Agile methodologies and have a history of meeting project deadlines.

EXPERIENCE

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

November 2023 – present

Exbito

Iran, Tehran

- Applied best practices in semantic HTML and modular CSS to maintain clean, effic, efficient, and accessible code.
- Collaborated effectively with UX/UI design teams to translate wireframes and designs into functional, high-quality code within Agile development cycles.
- Developed new forms and tables, reducing development time by 40 percent
- Enhanced site interactivity and user engagement by integrating JavaScript, HTML5, and CSS3 animations and transitions.

Technologies: Next.jsReact.js, Javascript,Typescript,QraphQl, SCSS, Styled Component,

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

January 2022 – August 2023

Beeptunes-Tapsell

Iran, Tehran

- Improved system management by rebuilding the legacy admin panel using React.js.
- Experienced with web performance optimization techniques such as code minification, image optimization, and lazy loading
- Understanding of accessibility and SEO principles, Implemented semantic HTML and ARIA attributes to improved accessibility.
- Mentored and Guided an intern in Frontend development
- Developed new forms and tables, reducing development time by 40 percent
- Demonstrated technical skills and ability to deliver high-quality solutions as a senior developer.

Technologies: React.js, Javascript, SCSS, Redux, Next.js

FRONT-END DEVELOPER(remote)

July 2020–December 2020

Menew

Iran, Tehran

- Designed tools and scripts to provide support to projects as per requirements.
- Built personalized and customized features for users

- Determined job priorities for multiple projects and communicated sequencing, priorities, and timelines to the entire team
- Understanding of RESTful APIs and experience integrating with back-end systems

Technologies: Html, CSS, SCSS, Javascript, Vue.js

Intern Frontend Developer

February 2020–August 2020

Iran, Tehran

• Built personalized and customized features for users

• Analysis and optimized pages as much as possible

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Digikala Next

Languages: JavaScript, Typescript

Frontend: React, Redux, Tailwind Css, React Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, SCSS,

SASS, Qraph Ql, Styled Component, Rest API

Developer Tools: Git, VS Code

Testing: jest

Soft Skills: Agile, Scrum, Pair programming

LANGUAGES

• English: Fluent

EDUCATION

Semnan University

Semnan, Iran

Associate in software engineering

September 2015 - August 2017

Islamic Azad University

Tehran, Iran

Bachelor of Computer Software Engineering

September 2017 - August 2021